The Electrical Life of Louis Wain is a drama, history,
comedy film directed by Will Sharpe.
The extraordinary true story of eccentric British artist Louis Wain, whose playful, sometimes even
psychedelic pictures helped to transform the public's perception of cats forever.
Louis Wain, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Emily Wain, played by Claire Foy.
Caroline Wain, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Sir William Ingram, played by Toby Jones.
Josephine Wain, played by Sharon Rooney.
Claire Wain, played by Aimee Lou Wood.
The Electrical Life of Louis Wain is a 2021 biographical comedy-drama film directed by Will
Sharpe, from a story by Simon Stephenson, and screenplay by Stephenson and Sharpe.
The film stars Benedict Cumberbatch (as the eccentric artist Louis
Wain), Claire Foy, Andrea Riseborough and Toby Jones.
The Electrical Life of Louis Wain had its world premiere at the 48th Telluride Film Festival on 2 September 2021,  had a
limited release on 22 October 2021, and was released in the United States on Prime Video on 5 November 2021.
It was released in the United Kingdom on 1 January 2022, by StudioCanal.
The film explores themes of inventor, affectation,
based on true story, angry, 19th century.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.